

ABDULHAKEEM ABIOYE

Oxford, Oxfordshire OX3 9NQ

+447895680135

wisdomabioye@gmail.com • https://abkabioye.me

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Seasoned software developer with more than 6 years of experience. Committed to providing high-level solutions that drive business and provide outstanding cost efficiency. Seeking an engaging position to provide top-notch solutions as part of a progressive team.

EDUCATION

Master of Science - MS:

Environmental Impact Assessment and Management, May 2023 Oxford Brookes University - Oxford, OXF

JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structure: Programming, 2016 FreeCodeCamp

Bachelor's degree: Geology/Earth

Science, 2015

Federal University of Technology -Minna

Diploma: Frontend and Backend Programming Basics, 2010

Lovelamp Systems - Ibadan

EXPERIENCE

Lead Developer, 09/2018 to 03/2022 Exclusive Platform - Ibadan, Nigeria

- Produce detailed program codes and specifications
- Test software products to ensure strong functionality and optimization
- Ensure the team of developers followed software quality guidelines.

Web Developer, 04/2016 to 08/2018 Simulate Link Nigeria Enterprises - Minna, Nigeria

- Implement website and integrate solutions into business operations
- Ensures smooth running of a web application for daily workflow

Instructor in Web Development, 01/2015 to 03/2016 Lovelamp Systems and Consulting Firm - Ibadan, Nigeria

- Educate students on HTML, CSS and JavaScript programming language, utilizing instructional techniques, including a hands-on curriculum.
- Design and update all instructional materials for IT programs on a regular basis.
- Create guides and course materials to reiterate lecture information and help students.

Professional Freelancer, 01/2011 to 03/2014 Rockstar Softlogic - Minna, Nigeria

- Propose, design and develop a website or an application for corporate organization/enterprise
- Repairs laptops for lecturers and students
- Fixes mobile phones (Blackberry and Android OS) software problems
- Prepares presentation and word document using Microsoft office.

CORE QUALIFICATIONS

- JavaScript & Libraries
- HTML & CSS
- Node.js, Express & Modules
- MongoDB
- Mongoose
- React
- Web3 & Blockchain Integration
- Solidity
- Typescript
- Next.js

- OS Installation
- Linux & Windows
- MS Office (Excel, Powerpoint, Word)
- Computer Maintenance
- AppEngine, Cloud Functions, Vercel
- Communication skills
- Problem-solving
- Fast Learner + Time Management